外键约束保证了表之间的链接
The foreign key constraint keeps the link between the tables
这是通过避免无效数据插入外键列来做到的
by preventing invalid data from being inserted into the foreign key column,
因为这个值必须包含在
because the value has to be one of the values contained in
表的约束值当中
the table the constraint points to.
那么这对于测试意味着什么呢
Well, what does this mean for testing?
它意味着我们不能在没有位置表的情况下测试天气表
It means that we cannot test the weather table without having the location table,
因为外键约束强制要求位置表的ID
because the foreign key constraint enforces that the location ID is a valid
在表中是一个可用的ID
ID in the location table.
这同样意味着我们必须使用插入位置表的结果
It also means that we have to use the result of an insert in the location
以便向天气表插入数据
table in order to insert in the weather table.
换句话说
In other words,
天气表不可能独立于位置表进行单元测试
the weather table cannot be unit tested independently from the location table.
我们现在就来为sunshine写一个数据库测试
We are going to be writing a database test for sunshine,
这其中就包含着一个约束
which will have to work with a constraint.